Your favorite nonprofit is becoming a
monopoly. OpenAI is now worth $500
billion. They just signed deals with
Nvidia, Oracle, and AMD. They're
consuming more energy than a small
country, and they replaced your startup
before you even start it. And they're
going to do it with the Chad GBD
ecosystem. See, OpenI plans to build
Chat GBD into the Everything app, making
sure that us, the users, never leave the
comforts of the chat. During their
recent dev day, they announced apps SDK.
This allows Chad GBD to use any app or
website on the internet. So, they're not
just trying to become the next browser.
They want Chad GBD to be the next
operating system. Oh, and they also
released agent kit, which is a brand new
way of building AI agents. It's
basically their own version of NA10.
Yeah, OpenAI is showing total
domination. CHGBT recently reached 800
million weekly active users. Also, their
recent 500 billion valuation puts them
ahead of SpaceX, making OpenAI the most
valuable startup in the world. And now
they want to take over the entire
internet. This is the map of all of the
companies that OpenAI is working with.
It feels like every month they're
signing a new multiund billion deal and
this is what's making them unstoppable.
So, OpenAI has a ruthless strategy that
not enough people are talking about and
this is how they replace startups and
how they choose which startups to
replace. They make their AI models
available through their OpenAI API and
then they watch carefully what others
build, what features, what products,
what services you create powered by
their own AI models. And then, and this
is the ruthless part, they attack and
replace the startups with the most
revenue growth. the startups that reach
product market fit and have the fastest
growth. That's where OpenAI comes in and
they build their own version of the same
product or service. And the man behind
the strategy is of course Sam Alman, the
CEO of OpenAI. Now, love him or hate
him, Sam Olman is one of the greatest
entrepreneurs of this generation. Nobody
can dispute that. He's the CEO of a 500
billion company. He's front running a
entire technological revolution,
probably the biggest technology shift in
the history of humanity. And he's doing
all of that while being just 40 years
old. And it's not like there's no
competition. He's competing with some of
the greatest entrepreneurs of all time.
Elon Musk, Mark Zuckerberg, Larry Page.
These are some of the most successful
and most powerful people in the world.
Yet Sam still seems to be winning. So
here's the plan. I'll show you how
people like me and you can actually
benefit from this OpenAI takeover thanks
to the apps SDK. We'll also look at how
to build a agents with the new agent kit
because this is a completely new era as
well as how it compares to NA10 make.com
and Zapier. And and this is my favorite
part will break down how OpenAI was able
to ship a multi-year project, a project
that would take other companies five
plus years in just 6 weeks thanks to
their new codec. So, first here is Sam
introducing the apps SDK.
>> Today we're launching the apps SDK. With
the apps SDK, you get the full stack.
You can connect your data, trigger
actions, render a fully interactive UI,
and more. When you build with the apps
SDK, your apps can reach hundreds of
millions of ChatGBT users. Basically,
Chad GBT is becoming an app store. The
apps SDK clearly shows us how OpenAI
plans to take over the internet. Their
goal is for the average person, the
typical user to do everything from
ChaiBT. So, you won't go to booking.com
to book your hotel. You'll do it by
asking CHBT. And that way, you never
leave the website. Now, this can either
make or break your business depending on
what strategy you take.
>> When someone's using chatbt, you'll be
able to find an app by asking for it by
name. For example, you could sketch out
a product flow for chatbt and then say,
"Figma, turn the sketch into a workable
diagram. We're also making apps
discoverable right in the conversation.
When a user asks for something, we can
surface a relevant app as a
recommendation."
>> Now, let's look at the bright side
because maybe the move isn't to fight
OpenAI. Maybe the move is to join them
and benefit from their rise. So all of
us that have a product or website, we
can take the product and using the app's
SDK build a CH GBT native app. This will
allow you to tap the 800 plus million
weekly active users who can now discover
your business right from CH GBT. But
apps SDK is just the beginning because
OpenAI also released agent kit.
>> Agent Kit is a complete set of building
blocks available in the OpenAI platform
designed to help you take agents from
prototype to production. It is
everything you need to build, deploy,
and optimize agentic workflows.
>> Here is the craziest part. Agent Kit was
built in 6 weeks. That's right. This
entire platform that allows you to build
and deploy AI agents was developed in
just 6 weeks. This is the power of AI.
And as Signal says here, this is truly
ridiculous. If you're a startup, you
might think, okay, I'm not going to play
the same game or I'm going to work 96
127. But the truth is you will never
outship AI. If you refuse to use AI
tools like Codex, you will simply lose.
That is the cold hard truth. And OpenAI
just walk the walk. They just
demonstrated how fast you can move
thanks to AI agents like Codex, which by
the way also got major updates, which
we'll cover in a bit. Now, that fact
that they shipped it in just 6 weeks,
becomes that much crazier when you
realize that agent kit involves another
tool named chatkit. The second thing is
chatkit. We're making it easy to bring
great chat experiences right into your
own apps. You get a simple embeddible
chat interface that you can make your
own. You can bring your own brand, your
own workflows, whatever makes your own
product unique. And you can see in the
video here how chat can work across each
agent node and call on tools to form the
best response. So the way to understand
chatkit is that you can now have CHIGBT
in your site. So if you don't want to
take the strategy of building a app with
apps SDK and putting that into CHBT, you
can still benefit from CIGBD by
embedding it into your site. So chatkit
gives you a readymade chat interface.
You can customize and add into your
website or your app. So just look at
some of these examples on the right.
These are called widgets and you can
have these directly in the chat
interface. So these can be outputed and
interacted by CH GBD. So it's not just
pure text and it's very clear that
OpenAI is trying to move away from just
being text right like large language
models next token prediction these are
paradigms that are inherently limiting
text is great it's better than nothing
but it's the biggest issue with all of
this chat user interface right just
having text we need another modality
whether it's images audio voice video or
these custom UI elements also known as
widgets so let's look at how OpenAI was
able to do all of this in just 6 weeks
And that is thanks to Codex.
>> Earlier this year, we launched a
research preview of Codeex. It works
everywhere you code. Now, your chat GBT
account connects everything so you can
move your work seamlessly between your
tools. We've released a ton of new
features for Codeex and it now runs on
the new GPT5 codeex model, a version of
GPT5 purposely trained for codeex and
Aenta coding. This model is better at
tasks like code refactoring and code
review and it can dynamically adjust its
thinking time for the complexity of the
task. a new codeex SDK so that you can
extend and automate codecs in your
team's own workflows.
>> So I know a lot of softwares are are
claiming to be the cloth code killer but
Codex is the only one that actually has
any validity to this statement. So if
you don't know Codex is OpenAI's coding
agent and it got upgraded yet again. Now
I would say it was already the best
because I use it more than CL code and I
trust it way more than Cloud Code at the
moment. But now it got another major
upgrade and that's because OpenAI
released Codex SDK and this allows me
and you to see inside the agent
framework. So unlike Enthropic which
they're refusing to make cloud code open
source, OpenAI just made Codex
completely open source. So we can look
inside, we can see the prompting
techniques, the agent orchestration and
what it takes to build a powerful coding
agent like Codex. So basically now Codex
can do everything from pull request
reviews to long running refactors
literally multiple hours to working on
20 plus tasks asynchronously in the
cloud. It really is the ultimate coding
AI agent. But first of all, if we go
back to our app right here, let's see if
we can actually control this camera now
with this Xbox controller. There we go.
It works.
That's pretty awesome. What's funny is
like I didn't even specify to Codex
which button should do what, but it
figured that the joystick was probably a
good idea. So that's that's actually
perfect.
>> Now we have to address something
uncomfortable because during the live
stream, OpenI tried very hard to hide
the most obvious takeaway and that is
all of these improvements and
advancements have a real cost to the
people who do not adapt, the people who
don't pay attention, right? Not
everybody watches videos like this one.
Not everybody is paying attention to the
latest AI advancements. And the truth is
is that those people their jobs will be
replaced. You could see it throughout
this presentation if you actually paid
attention in multiple different roles.
Camera operators, the light technicians,
translators, radiologists, teachers,
real estate agents, tour guides. I mean
they literally showed how they would
replace all the tour guides in
Versailles in Paris. All of those jobs
will be done better with AI. Now
obviously open will never say this but
anybody who spends 5 seconds thinking
about it will realize that we only have
two choices. Either adapt or get
replaced. Now to make you even more
uncomfortable there's going to be a
complete divide of how AI impacts you.
People with high IQ will become
superhuman. You'll be able to automate
all the repetitive with AI agents
and you'll be able to build stuff, build
custom software 50 times faster than you
could otherwise. However, people with
less than average IQ will become likely
addicted to AI generated content.
Obviously, not all of them, but in
general, the masses will be deceived by
AI videos, AI images, AI voices, and
they'll fall into AI powered propaganda.
And the unfortunate and uncomfortable
truth is that God or the universe,
whatever you believe, has decided your
destiny a long time ago because you
cannot really choose which of these
categories you're in. So, in a way, your
destiny has already been decided. This
brings up the topic of the slob machine,
right? The release of SAR 2, which is
like what, two weeks ago? It's crazy. AI
is moving so fast. Feels like forever
ago. But yeah, SA 2 just released as
well. And it took the realism of AI
videos to the next level, right?
Literally, some of them you cannot even
tell. And now after the dev day, SAR 2
is available in the API, right? Right?
So what that means is that people can
build on top of this video model which
means we will see even more AI slope.
Now like it or not this is probably what
the future of entertainment is going to
look like. It's going to be AI generated
videos that are highly stimulating to
the brain. And you might think okay I'm
just going to watch other entertainment
but you will not know. Now we can still
tell but in 6 months nobody will be able
to tell. Now what's funny is that even
Mr. Mr. Beast himself who is the king of
entertainment you know the king of
content of attentiongrabbing slop is
worried about AI right so Mr. calls out
AI as threat to YouTubers, Livelihood
says, "Scary times." So, the most
successful creator of manual slop is now
worried about AI slope. So, that's kind
of funny, but honestly, this is not
really an issue for those who create
content that isn't slop, right? So, the
way I was able to summarize this into a
single sentence is if you are in
entertainment, pivot to education. If
you are creating a content that's not
valuable, doesn't bring any unique
insight, any unique ideas, novel
analysis, nothing inherent of value,
you're just doing the same that
everybody else is doing. Don't be
surprised when AI replaces you as well.
And this is a very bullish message to
those who are making educational high-v
value content that is much harder to
replicate, right? Content in flesh. When
you show up in flesh, you know it's
something of value. Now back to the
positive side because we spend a bit too
much on the doomer side. But the fact is
that agents are going to be available
for everyone. Even if you aren't a
programmer, even if you have zero
skills, the release of agent kit is
fundamentally revolutionary. It will
allow millions of new people to build AI
agents, right? Even though tools like
natake.com have existed for a while,
OpenAI backing something, right? OpenAI
creating their own agent builder will
expose it to millions, if not tens of
millions of potential new AI agent
builders. Now, I have to be fair. The
agent kit is similar to anything or
make.com, right? It's not like they
invented the light bulb. It's not a
radical new technology, but it is a much
cleaner and simpler design. It is easier
to use. It's more userfriendly, but it
also does include some new features and
some new tools that other platforms
don't have. And so, in a second, I'll
show you how you can start using Agent
Kit yourself. But first, hear it from
Sam on what it actually is.
>> This is a canvas to build agents. It's a
fast visual way to design the logic
steps, test the flows, and ship ideas.
It's built on top of the responses API
that hundreds of thousands of developers
already use.
>> All right, so now let's look at how to
actually use agent kit. First, we need
to go to Google while it still exists
and type in platform OpenAI and click on
the first link. Then you need to login
with your CHBT account. So in the top
right, click on your account and use the
same one as using CHBT. Takes 20
seconds. Then click on dashboard which
will bring you here but then on the left
you can see agent builder and this is
where agent kit is located. So click on
agent builder and you can either create
a workflow from scratch or you can use
one of these uh six templates. They're
probably going to add more let's be
honest. So they have data enrichment
planning helper customer service
structure data QA document comparison
and internal knowledge assistant.
Honestly probably data enrichment sounds
the most interesting. So let's explore
this template. And there it is. Here is
the dashboard. You can see this one is
very simple. We have the start node.
Then we have a web research agent and
the summarize and display agent. Simple
workflow to research a set of companies
using web search and provide summary
analysis. Analyze Nvidia. Find a company
using web search. Okay. So this is very
simple agent. Preview this. And this is
nice. So you can see how it works by
testing it right away with like a chat
style interface. Analyze OpenAI dev day.
Let's use it on their own product. So
there we go. start web research agent is
going and then you're going to summarize
and display this you can obviously do
inside of JBT itself but I think this is
just an introduction to how the agent
kit could be used the first templates
probably the simplest one the beauty is
that you can see like the logs and all
of this lives within open ecosystem so
debugging this and building on top of
this will be very very nice very clean
all right so here we have the response
view details
I mean this is nothing crazy, right? So
let's look at some other We lost the
templates. Oh no. Okay, so this crazy.
If you use any of them, you lose them.
Okay, we still have the templates here.
Yeah, keep in mind that as soon as you
click on templates, you seem to lose
them. That's kind of crazy. Let's see
which of these is more. Okay, let's look
at document comparison. Okay, this one
is more advanced. So by the way, on the
left we have the different notes, right?
So the core is agent, we have end note
and note. So this is a sticky note. This
is built with React Flow by the way. So
if you want to build an app like this
yourself, React Flow is a way to do
that. Pretty easy. So OpenAI again, they
ship this in six weeks thanks to Codex.
It's pretty impressive. I think each
workflow comes with a pre-created start
note start define a workflow inputs
input variable input as text string.
Very simple. This is clearly targeted
for non-developers. So then we have the
agent. This is probably going to be the
main node name agent. You can rename it.
Instructions, the system prompt, include
chat history. So, you can easily toggle
this if the chat history shouldn't be
included. And then model, you probably
choose all of them, right? Nano GP5 Pro,
that's another thing that released in
dev day. GBD5 Pro is now in the API.
4.1, I would recommend 4.1. Actually, a
lot of people want to use GPD5 because
it's newer, but for AI agents, GPD 4.1
is much more reliable. Then tools, you
can add bunch of tools. chat kit, MCP
server, file search, web search, code
interpreter or a custom function, output
format, text or JSON. Wow. So you don't
even have to instruct it to output
structure. You can just select it here
and then widget which is chatkit. This
is actually pretty good. You can do like
some major prompt engineering here.
You can add multiple different prompts.
User assistant. Oh wow. So you can
construct the conversation history
already. So this is like the system
prompt. Look at this. We have assistant
prompt. Then we have the first user
prompt. Then we can do assistant message
response and then user again. So you can
literally like this is one of the
advanced pro engineing principles. You
can prefill the conversation, right? So
it looks like it already starts. Nice.
This is nice. And then sticky notes are
just for explaining your workflow. And
then we have tools like file search. So
this is the vector DB. Okay. So you need
to create it inside of the vector
storage in OpenAI. So they're going to
use their embedding tool to create a
highdimensional vector database or
vector store for this you know probably
not a database if it's a single file but
yeah and then you can use those inside
of your workflow you can choose the k
nearest neighbors select 10
and the query on how to cue it
guardrails this is I think something
that is the differentiator between agent
kit and you know n10.com guardrails
input as text personally and okay so we
can clean personal undevelopable
information moderation like harmful
content or you know 18 plus content
jailbreaking. So if you're building this
as a back end, you know, you know the
meme like lovable front end anytime back
end, you can do like agent kit back end.
You can literally build and this is the
crazy part. You can turn this into code,
right? So using agents SDK, you can uh
copy paste this into your Python back
end and uh build on top of it. And by
the way, this would this might be a
whole new video. Like if you want me to
make a video on how to build an AI agent
with agent kit and then deploy it into
your Python back end so you can build on
top of it and build a whole startup with
this comment below because uh that's
fascinating the fact that you can just
click on code and instantly copy it and
build your own application around it
powered by agent kit. See, OpenAI
destroyed hundreds of startups with this
dev day, but they just made thousands of
new startups possible that before were
either not possible or at least like 50
times 100 times harder. You cannot like
fully criticize OpenAI, but you cannot
fully love them either. MCP. So, this is
interesting. People talking about like
how Enthropic invented MCPs, but OpenAI
is actually the one that's capitalizing
on them. So, we have MCP node. So, you
can integrate u MCP servers. Now, Agent
Kit might not have as many integrations
as other agent builders, but they do
have the MCP node, and that's really all
you need because there's an MCP that
lets you connect to over 500 different
apps. And that MCP is called RUP. So, if
you're in agent kit and you activate the
MCP node and you click on add, here you
can add any MCP server. And if you add
RUP, you can connect over 500 different
apps through a single MCB connector. So
whether that is Gmail, Slack,
Perplexity, YouTube, GitHub or
Superbase, RP has it all. And the best
part is you can just tell it what apps
you want to connect together. Like in
this example where you ask it to add a
marketing deck from Google Drive into
your Slack and it calls the tool and
does that. Or maybe you need RP to write
a follow-up email. Well, it can use the
Gmail.create email draft tool and do
exactly that. So instead of having to
connect all of these MCPS one by one,
all you have to do is connect RP and it
gives you all of these apps with it. And
thanks to the free plan, you can start
using RP today completely for free. So
if you want to connect over 500
different apps through a single MCP, go
to rub.app and give it a shot or just
click the link below the video. Thanks
to RP for sponsoring today's upload. If
else. Okay, so we have basic u
programming logic while loop and then
some data transform or set state. So
these are already NA10 obviously. So
let's look at this one. Start triage
request. Let's see what's this. So this
is an AI agent. Classify the user's
request based on whether two documents
have been provided recently in the
conversation. Propose reconciliation. So
these are all agents. This is
interesting. This is a very interesting
looking at this from the design choice.
Right? In NA10 you have an AI agent.
It's like a big node, a big block,
right? Here like the if else is much
bigger than agent. They make the agent
like a small thing here. And then this
is like three agents here. It's no big
deal. Just customize each agent for each
scenario. This is a very interesting
design choice how OpenAI thinks
differently about the significance of an
agent in a workflow compared to NA10.
Yeah, this is looks much more like
streamlined, simpler. Doesn't mean it's
better. NA10 is obviously more advanced.
NA10 has way more integrations.
But again, OpenI shipped this in six
weeks. And this a lot of beginners will
use this, right? because the UI is more
clean. OpenAI designers are amazing. Uh
their I'm jealous of their UIUIX. Um
yeah, if I had the budget, I would
probably poach some of these designers
to be honest. But yeah, um no nothing
crazy here. It goes to an AI agent, then
it goes to user approval. If it's a
rejection agent, they're just spamming
AI agents. Like you could probably put
some loop in here, right? But uh whoever
designed this template is just not
afraid to spam agent everywhere. And the
output format is a test widget. Look at
this. Preview code, detach, edit. So
this is chatkit, by the way. So if
you're confused uh by all the releases,
you're not the only one. But chatkit
basically lets you build these widgets,
right? Which is like UI elements.
Basically, this is like their own
version of chat. Honestly, I might be
talking complete now, so feel free
to correct me in the comments, but uh
yeah, this this feels uh like their own
kind of UI framework. I mean they their
own way of letting you build with their
own UI design system basically. So you
have the playground, you have the widget
builder and the chatkit world. That's
like a demo. So you can do a new widget,
you can see a gallery of pre-built
widgets, right? So like a calendar.
Yeah. So basically this is like OpenAI
designed components that they're kind of
letting you borrow but not fully because
you have to stay in their ecosystem,
right? Button. Okay. So you can build
websites that look polished with this
date picker. I mean other websites you
know they I don't think they let you u
take it fully. Let's see if this is the
case or not. Did openi fully open source
chat kit and all the elements inside? I
highly doubt it but this is nice. Like
we have a bunch of icons like 50 or
whatever. Obviously not as much as some
other open source libraries. The point
is that you can easily design these UI
widgets or UI elements with um you know
very simple HTML style code and you can
use these inside of your agent kit apps
right this is this chatkit let's see no
openi did not fully open source chatk
kit here's what available openi released
chatkit javascript components under the
apache 2.0 license. This includes
chatkit, react components. Okay, this
might be a whole another video like how
to build websites in the style of
chatkit, you know, with these
components, chart, icon, image,
markdown, label, caption, title, and
obviously you can do a new widget and
you can just describe it using plain
English and GPT will build it for you.
Agents MD. Okay, so here's the system
prompt. Nice. They revealed the system
prompt. You are an expert widget
designer and developer. Outputs must be
small compact widgets. Methodal
methodology,
complexity, budgets. What are widgets?
Widgets UI. Widget is a strict
simplified version of JSX that only
permits specific components and props.
Wow. They open source the whole prompt.
And this is a long prompt, guys. I'm
still scrolling. This is a very long
prompt. Oh my god, guys. We need to
study this. Wait, how long is this?
8,000 words, 55,000 characters. Guys, if
your prompts are not this long, maybe
you are not serious. Maybe you don't
really care about your AI agents. This
is a complete prompt engineering
masterass here from OpenAI.
They just gave away how to prompt AI
agents. Wow. That that's that's amazing.
That's actually amazing that they open
source the agents MD. I clicked that
completely by accident. But hey, I bet
most people have skipped that and missed
that. But this is what you get by
watching the David Andre channel. If you
aren't subscribed yet, go below video
and click subscribe. It takes two
seconds and the benefits are tremendous.
It's a no-brainer deal. Uh it's a grand
slam offer as Hermosi would say. But
yeah, this is the agents widget builder
for aka also known as chatkit. It's not
fully open source, but they did give us
the components, some sample
applications, documents, and guide.
What's not open source? the core chatkit
infrastructure remains proprietary back
and services agent builder okay it's
hybrid so so the UI components are open
source and some of these icons so that's
nice yeah anyways as I said this is a
whole new video minimum this is like
probably multiple videos so if you want
a full dedicated video on using agent
kit but more importantly the code right
how to deploy this into your own
application and there's also evas we
haven't even touched on evas yeah
there's a lot uh openi is cooking and
wow guys we live in the future. We live
in the future and u openai is about to
monopolize the entire internet if nobody
stops them. Well let me know which
videos you want me to make whether agent
kit and how to build a whole application
with this or whether chat kit and going
more into these components UI um how to
build your own widget. There is so much
content it's crazy. So let me know which
one I should make or if I should make
all of them. That being said, if you
watch until the end, thank you. Thank
you for watching and I wish you a
wonderful, productive week.